

# ABOUT ME

Hey, Kate here. I have experience working on successful business software at Microsoft. I have shipped many different products including complex site diagnostic tools, business dashboards, flow diagrams, data visualization, and easy to use account sign up flows.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

## PayPal / User Experience Designer - Contractor

Austin, TX | February 2021 - July 2021

· Worked on Migration flow for Zettle and SSO login flows for PayPal.

## Microsoft / User Experience, Product Designer - Contractor

Redmond, WA | July 2019 - November 2020

- · Redesigned SharePoint template gallery.
- · Designed webpage speed and weight diagnostic tools.
- · Worked on Power BI and SharePoint Integration.
- · Experimented with onboarding and learning experiences.

## Istrolid 2 computer game / Freelance UX/UI Designer

San Francisco, CA | May 2018 - March 2019

- · Visual design for game interfaces and hierarchy of game screens.
- · Experience design for the main menu and widgets.

## Waterpark / Freelance Visual Designer

San Francisco, CA | August 2018 - August 2018

· Logo design, icon design, and branding.

### Gravitational Inc / UX Designer - Full time

Oakland, CA | October 2017 - April 2018

- · Primary designer at Gravitational Inc.
- · Created the visual design language with a full icon set.
- · UX/UI design for open source documentation.

#### **EDUCATION**

## **Academy of Art University**

San Francisco, CA | January 2014 - May 2017

Bachelor of Web Design & New Media

### City College of San Francisco

San Francisco, CA | January 2011 - January 2014

General Education in Business

### **Altai State University**

Barnaul, Russia | September 2007 - May 2009

Associate of Asian Studies

kate.vonhouck.com kate@vonhouck.com

#### **SKILLS**

#### **Software**

Figma

Sketch

Invision

Adobe CS

Keynote

Power BI

SharePoint

## Design

Storyboarding

Wireframing

Prototyping

Branding

Data Visualization

Visual Design

Interaction Design

Motion Design

Style Guides

#### Research

Persona

User Interviews

**Usability Testing** 

Competitive Analysis

A/B Testing

Experiments

Task Analysis

Persona Hypothesis

### **Programming**

HTML/CSS

JavaScript

Swift

### Languages

English

Russian

Mandarin